A Guide to the John Gneisenau Neigardt Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8329
John Gneisenau Neigardt Collection 1920-1966
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8329
13 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1966 Aug 30
Item Listing
- Letters
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, 1920 Dec 2; TLS, 3 p.
    [Refers to paintings in a building in Nebraska(State Capitol ?), and his feelings about the Goodhue plan; wonders if anyone has suggested displaying General Ashley's expedition; mentions his work,
    The Splendid Wayfarer
    , as it tells the whole story of the Ashley expedition.]
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, 1921 Jun 27; TLS, 1 p. w/env
    [Thanks him for his kindness in managing the "affair of the 18th"; promises to reward his kindness through loyalty and good work.]
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, 1921 Jul 1; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for a fine editorial on his work; gives him a selection of his lyrics which he suggests be printed in the newspaper; mentions his progress with
    The Song of the Indian Wars
    , which he considers his greatest achievement.]
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, 1921 Jul 24; TLS, 1 p. w/env
    [Thanks him for another "bully" editorial; expresses gratitude for seeing his poems published in the newspaper as he wants Nebraskans, of all people, to know him; gives progress report on
    claims that he is not working for personal advantage; regards all who help as collaborators.] (includes autograph notations)
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, 1921 Aug 2; TLS, 1 p. w/env
    [Asks him for copies of his, as well as Professor Reed's, Dean Sherman's, and Mr. Brown's speeches, given at the Temple on June 18, to be published in Chicago. ]
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, 1923 Jun 3; TLS, 1 p. w/env
    [Apologizes for long delay in sending promised letter to Richard G. Moulton, England; mentions daughter's operation and hard physical labor to which he is not accustomed; includes progress report on
    . ] (Includes autograph notations)
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, 1923 Nov 4; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Reports on the "good and profitable time" he had in Washington talking with old Indian fighters of the plains; says he has had good audiences; mentions speaking engagement with the young ladies of Hood College in Frederick; says he "compromised on lyrics" but was kept going a long time; regards the students as "very discerning"; speculates on the possibility of occupying the Chair of Poetry at the University of Nebraska. ]
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, 1924 Feb 9; TLS, 1 p.
    [Reports on a 6 week speaking tour through Texas and the progress of his book; thanks him for copy of
    By Land and Sea
    . ]
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, 1924 Oct 21; ALS, 2 p. w/env
    [Requests that a copy of the
    Sunday Journal
    be sent to his wife as it contains Jones' remarks on Neigardt's trip to Lincoln, Nebraska; says he is pleased with receptions of his speaking tour, but he is too tired to take on more assignments.]
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Editor, The Literary Review [ Will Orton Tewson], 1925 Aug 4; TLS, 2 p.
    [Answers the question, "What is the most beautiful line of poetry in the English language?" by directing the editor's attention to his forthcoming book
    More Truth than Poetry
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, Wednesday noon; ALS, 1 p.
    [Gives him the dates of several of his speaking engagements.]
  - John Gneisenau Neigardt to Will Owen Jones, Friday A. M.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Writes about a meeting with Professor A. A. Reed pertaining to getting the Professorship at the University of Nebraska; says that permanent residence in Lincoln appeals to him.]
- Miscellaneous
  - Printed Bible announcement, 1921 Aug 4; Family Record
    [Birth of daughter Alice Neigardt. ]